Mohammed Mahdi Akkouh

Senior Quant Developer @ ANZ

akkouh.mahdi@gmail.com

Summary

I develop and deliver pricing solutions in the financial industry and have over 8 years of experience within banks. I am engaged, punctual, and cost-oriented, and my primary objective is to satisfy the end user by providing quality, reliable service. I enjoy finding elegant solutions to simplify and improve systems while complying with in-house practices. In addition I have experience managing and guiding teams through the development-testing-production cycle. I am constantly engaged in learning new subjects, such as web technologies, machine learning, big data, and statistics. And, in my free time, I enjoy rowing.

Experience

Senior Quantitative Developer at ANZ

March 2015 - Present (7 months)

Developing and maintaining the analytics library.

Team Leader, Analytics at Natixis

October 2013 - March 2015 (1 year 6 months)

- Project-managed a team of 11 persons in charge of the development-test-delivery process of the analytics library and Summit addins Defined, documented processes and assured training Conceived solutions for trading desks and risk services Secured/improved the development-test-delivery cycle by lowering operational risks and accelerating the frequency of delivery (delivering every 2 weeks down from 6/8 weeks)
- Technologies: Summit addins, C/C++, Git, Shell scripts, Jenkins

Quantitative Developer at Natixis

April 2008 - September 2013 (5 years 6 months)

- Worked within the IR analytics team - Developed IR exotic pricers - Collaborated with quantitative analysts in designing and crafting a new analytics library for vanilla IR assets pricing - Improved and maintained IR curves for trading desks: OIS discounting, Short Term electronic trading, refactoring the LIBOR stripper - Technologies: C/C++, Visual Studio - Designed and built a grid-computing solution for pricing and hedging exotic IR assets (few minutes of calculation time down from 1 hour) - Migrated the analytics library to Solaris. - Technologies: Datasynapse, C/C++, boost, Make, Bash

FO Trainee Egineer at BMCE Capital

February 2007 - September 2007 (8 months)

- Developed pricing tools for bonds, FXO and Var - Participated in the project management team in charge of implementing Basel II directives

Volunteer Experience

Volunteer at SIFE

2004 - 2006 (2 years)

Enriching experience, where I visited remote locations and met many people with real economic concerns. I had enjoyed working on the field and sharing experience.

Projects

Sport Social Network

August 2013 to May 2014

Members: Mohammed Mahdi Akkouh

Social Network for sport players using web technologies: Ruby 4, Rails 2, Postgresql, Bootstrap 3, GIT.

IR Exotic Generic Pricer

March 2011 to January 2013

Members: Mohammed Mahdi Akkouh

Based on lexical and grammatical analysers, implemented in Flex and Bison, this calculator can generate any payoff on the fly. Models and numerical methods can be plugged-in.

Skills & Expertise

Interest Rate Derivatives

Software Development

Financial Software Development

C/C++ STL

Web Development

Ruby on Rails

JavaScript

C++

Programming

Derivatives

Fixed Income

Structured Products

Investment Banking

Financial Modeling

Financial Risk

Electronic Trading

Trading

Project Management

Hedging

Education

SKEMA Business School

Postgraduate program, Financial Engineering, 2007 - 2008

Activities and Societies: IEEE

Ecole Nationale Supérieure d'Informatique et d'Analyse des Systèmes - ENSIAS

Engineer's degree, Computer Software Engineering, 2004 - 2007

Activities and Societies: SIFE: Students In Free Entreprise

Moulay Youssef High School

Classes Préparatoires aux Grandes Ecoles, Maths / Physics, 2002 - 2004

Certifications

Data Wrangling with MongoDB

Udacity July 2015

Intro to Data Science

Udacity April 2015

The Modern World: Global History since 1760

Coursera April 2013

Gamification

Coursera October 2012

Networked Life

Coursera October 2012

Game Theory

Coursera May 2012

Interests

web development, rowing, boxing

Languages

English

French

Arabic

Mohammed Mahdi Akkouh

Senior Quant Developer @ ANZ

akkouh.mahdi@gmail.com



Contact Mohammed Mahdi on LinkedIn